# SANDIP THAPA

Tinthana-14, Chandragiri, Bagmati Province, Nepal sandipthapa386@gmail.com (+977) 9808976977

A highly motivated and hard-working individual, graduate of Computer Science with above 3 years of active participation on software development. Wide range of technical skill-set and attention to detail. Loves to work in an environment where I could create digital magic and elevate user interface and experience to the next level.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**NOV 2023 - PRESENT** 

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ASTERDIO INC.**

- Develop multi language applications using i18n, Next-Intl, React.js and Next.js.
- Integrate Azure authentication using MSAL in an existing project
- Implement Microsoft Clarity as user behavior analytics tool.
- Work closely with other team members, including product managers, designers, and other developers while being assigned to multiple projects at once.

**JAN 2022 - OCT 2023** 

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- · Convert Figma designs into web pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop new user-facing features using React.js and Next.js with Typescript.
- Develop and maintain fast, bug-free, and re-usable components for the in-house product.
- Collaborate with design team to enhance user interfaces and its experience.
- Implement and manage version controlling of the project using git flow.

**SEPT 2021 - DEC 2021** 

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, EKBANA SOLUTIONS PTE. LTD.

- Developed supermarket app with React.js.
- API integration and data handling using Context API.
- Got to learn about Software Development Life Cycle using SCRUM.

#### **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2021

BSc (Hons) IT, HERALD COLLEGE, UNIVERSITY OF WOLVERHAMPTON

- Introduced to fundamentals of programming, Data Structure & Algorithms & DBMS.
- Assigned to multiple mini and group projects.
- Worked on different research, communication and collaboration skills.

2016 - 2018

INTERMEDIATE - SCIENCE, KATHMANDU BERNHARDT COLLEGE

• Majors: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

# **PROJECTS**

Mero Moto - Vehicle Buy/Sale Platform

Technologies: Next.js(SSR), Typescript, Mantine UI, Node.js

View Project (2)

Auto24 - Automobiles Dealership System

Technologies: React.js, Ant Design, Redux

Auctions by Auto24, Vehicles Auction Platform

Technologies: Next.js(SSG, ISR), Typescript, SCSS, Docker

View Project 🕜

### **KEY SKILLS**

• HTML5

• CSS3/SCSS/Tailwind CSS

Bootstrap5

Javascript

TypeScript

• React.js

Novt ic

Next.js

• React Query

- Mantine UI
- Ant Design
- FormikRedux
- Git
- Gitlab
- Docker
- Figma

- SCRUM
- Communication
- Team WorkCritical Thinking
  - Leadership

## SOCIAL ACCOUNTS

• Portfolio: <a href="https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/">https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/</a>

• LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/</a>

• **Github:** <a href="https://github.com/sandipthapa99/">https://github.com/sandipthapa99/</a>